<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>surveys on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/surveys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in surveys on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a nice place to live but I&#39;m not sure I want to stay here</title>
      <link>/2019/06/27/it-s-a-nice-place-to-live-but-i-m-not-sure-i-want-to-stay-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/27/it-s-a-nice-place-to-live-but-i-m-not-sure-i-want-to-stay-here/</guid>
      <description>From the Pew Research Center’s “2018 Local News Survey” is an interesting example of how the answer to a data analysis changes when you flip the question.
The data comes from the first two questions, which asked 34,897 people to rate the quality of living in their communities and how attached they feel to those communities.
LOCALRATING: Overall, how would you rate your community as a place to live?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump approval vs satisfaction with country&#39;s direction</title>
      <link>/2019/06/26/trump-approval-vs-satisfaction-with-country-s-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/26/trump-approval-vs-satisfaction-with-country-s-direction/</guid>
      <description>If you’re not sure whether you like the direction the country is heading toward, how likely are you to approve of President Trump’s job performance?
Taking a look at the Pew Research Center’s “September 2018 Political Survey,” the latest dataset publicly available on the center’s site, https://www.pewresearch.org/download-datasets/, the answer surprises me at least.
So if you’re not sure about the country’s direction, there’s a roughly equal chance that you approve of Trump’s job performance, disapprove or aren’t sure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
