<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pets on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/pets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pets on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The rise of &#34;Bella&#34; as a dog name in Allegheny County</title>
      <link>/2020/04/19/the-rise-of-bella-as-a-dog-name-in-allegheny-county/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/19/the-rise-of-bella-as-a-dog-name-in-allegheny-county/</guid>
      <description>Taking a break from coronavirus stats, I downloaded the latest data on Allegheny County dog licenses and found an interesting trend. If you look at the top 10 dog names in each year from 2007 to 2019, you’ll see that “Bella” doesn’t even make the list in 2007 but is the top name by 2019.
The data doesn’t include dogs licensed inside the city of Pittsburgh.
In general, the top 10 dog names in each year account for about 9 to 10 percent of all licensed dogs, so there’s a lot of diversity in dog names in the county.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity of dog names in Allegheny County</title>
      <link>/2019/02/19/popularity-of-dog-names-in-allegheny-county/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/19/popularity-of-dog-names-in-allegheny-county/</guid>
      <description>Bella has usurped Molly but Buddy can’t be beat when it comes to the most frequent names on dog licenses in Allegheny County.
The data comes from the Western Pennsylvania Regional Data Center, https://data.wprdc.org/dataset/allegheny-county-dog-licenses. It includes dogs licensed within the county but not those licensed inside the city of Pittsburgh.
County dog owners like a lot of variety in their pets’ names. While top names for each gender accont for about 400 to 500 names, about 30,000 dogs are licensed every year with the number of unique names ranging from 7,031 in 2016 to 8,929 in 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>