<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>County Revenues</title>
      <link>/2019/03/05/county-revenues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/05/county-revenues/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a quick look at county revenues. It includes the percent that comes from local taxes as well as the percent that comes from intergovernmental transfers from federal, state and other local government agencies.
{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;filter&#34;:&#34;top&#34;,&#34;filterHTML&#34;:&#34;\n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n \n&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pittsburgh&#39;s job trend</title>
      <link>/2019/02/21/pittsburgh-job-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/21/pittsburgh-job-trends/</guid>
      <description>How does Pittsburgh’s job trend compare to that of other metro areas?
Here’s the short answer showing the annual average total nonfarm payroll for each metro indexed to 2006.
The general trend line is shown in blue and Pittsburgh’s trend is shown in yellow. The metros are divided into four groups based on how their job growth generally compares to the overall trend line.
The clustering method I used put Pittsburgh in the “Slightly Better” group although that’s mainly based on its performance between 2008 and 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity of dog names in Allegheny County</title>
      <link>/2019/02/19/popularity-of-dog-names-in-allegheny-county/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/19/popularity-of-dog-names-in-allegheny-county/</guid>
      <description>Bella has usurped Molly but Buddy can’t be beat when it comes to the most frequent names on dog licenses in Allegheny County.
The data comes from the Western Pennsylvania Regional Data Center, https://data.wprdc.org/dataset/allegheny-county-dog-licenses. It includes dogs licensed within the county but not those licensed inside the city of Pittsburgh.
County dog owners like a lot of variety in their pets’ names. While top names for each gender accont for about 400 to 500 names, about 30,000 dogs are licensed every year with the number of unique names ranging from 7,031 in 2016 to 8,929 in 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public sector jobs in Pittsburgh and other metros</title>
      <link>/2019/02/17/public-sector-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/17/public-sector-jobs/</guid>
      <description>How does Pittsburgh’s public sector employment compare to that of other metro areas? In this first glance, I’m going to focus on what percentage of the metro area’s jobs are government jobs.
The data comes from the Bureau of Labor Statistics monthly survey of state and local employment. I use the annual averages, so the latest data is for 2017.
Looking at 444 metro areas in the 50 states, the District of Columbia and Puerto Rico, the concentration of public-sector employment in 2017 ranged from a low of 6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>