<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data_reporting on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/data_reporting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data_reporting on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/data_reporting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data reporting - combinations</title>
      <link>/2020/09/18/data-reporting-combinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/18/data-reporting-combinations/</guid>
      <description>One of the issues I occasionally run into is a need to create all possible combinations of two or more sets of strings.
For example, I’m currently taking a look at the weather data you can find here: https://www1.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/ghcn/daily/
The data consists of 115,076 fixed-width text files with a “.dly” extension. Each file contains the historic data from a single weather station. Each row of the data consists of the station’s id, the year and month the readings were taken and 31 sets of values with three flags for each value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data reporting - more scraping</title>
      <link>/2020/06/12/data-reporting-more-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/12/data-reporting-more-scraping/</guid>
      <description>A fellow reporter, Jason Kandel, asked me to look at how to use Google Sheets to scrape wildfire information from this site: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/accessible-view/
I’ve had mixed success using Google Sheets as a scraper but I managed to come up with a kludge that requires manual updates as fires get added to the list (which seems to be fairly often based on my limited experience with the site).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data reporting - web scraping basics</title>
      <link>/2020/06/11/analyzing-data-scraping-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/11/analyzing-data-scraping-basics/</guid>
      <description>A quick look at web scraping, data cleaning and data archivingThis is more of a quick look at something I recently learned than anything exhaustive on the subject. What I learned is how to use html_table() in the rvest package to save myself a lot of headaches when it comes to scraping.
Typically when I scrape data from the site I figure out how to grab individual pieces of data, pull them into lists and then create a tibble (data frame) from the lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data reporting - average percent change</title>
      <link>/2020/06/08/data-reporting-average-percent-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/08/data-reporting-average-percent-change/</guid>
      <description>Calculating the rate of changeWhen it comes to analyzing several observations over time, figuring out the average percent increase or decrease (i.e. growth rate) is a useful but potentially misleading tool. Looking over a city’s budget for the past five years, for example, you can see how the growth in spending and revenues compared to each other as well as inflation. Comparing county population growth rates over a few decades can help pinpoint the ones with consistent growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data reporting - analyzing occurrences</title>
      <link>/2020/06/07/data-reporting-analyzing-occurrences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/07/data-reporting-analyzing-occurrences/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing the frequency of occurrencesThis is the first in an occasional series of posts mainly geared toward other data journalists. In this post, I’m taking a look at how to calculate the frequency of occurrences in a time-series data. The question is a trivial one, but it does illustrate how data can change your thinking.
Netflix emailsI subscribed to Netflix in June 2019, primarily to watch Season 3 of Stranger Things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
