<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>misc on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in misc on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus stats</title>
      <link>/2020/04/01/coronavirus-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/01/coronavirus-stats/</guid>
      <description>I know there are a lot of visualizations dealing with the coronavirus, but sometimes I think they get so complex that they hide a few key points. So here’s my take on them using data from the European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control.
The obvious caveats are that the daily number of new Covid-19 cases and coronavirus-related deaths rely on the accurate testing of patients and the willingness of countries to share data with their own citizens and the rest of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Virginia has a higher density of churches than Pennsylvania</title>
      <link>/2019/12/28/west-virginia-has-more-churches-per-10-square-miles-than-pennsylvania/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/28/west-virginia-has-more-churches-per-10-square-miles-than-pennsylvania/</guid>
      <description>Although Pennsylvania has nearly twice the land area of West Virginia, their number of churches is almost the same, according to Census and U.S. Geological Survey data.
Oddly enough, the land area values come from the Census while the number of churches comes from the Geological Survey’s domestic names database, https://www.usgs.gov/core-science-systems/ngp/board-on-geographic-names/domestic-names.
I started taking a look at the database Friday (Dec. 27, 2019) and decided to see if the data confirmed my personal experience that West Virginia seemed to have more churches per square mile than Pennsylvania or pretty much any other place I’d ever lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have a lot of Guts</title>
      <link>/2019/12/27/we-have-a-lot-of-guts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/27/we-have-a-lot-of-guts/</guid>
      <description>It’s been some time since I posted anything, so when I stumbled across this today, I thought it was worth a mention. Perusing the U.S. Geological Survey’s database of domestic names, I discovered the types of named features is a “Gut.”
We have 3,497 of them.
What are they? It took some digging, but I found this 1987 data user’s guide that provides this definition: “relatively small coastal waterway connecting larger bodies of water or other waterways (creek, inlet, slough).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a nice place to live but I&#39;m not sure I want to stay here</title>
      <link>/2019/06/27/it-s-a-nice-place-to-live-but-i-m-not-sure-i-want-to-stay-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/27/it-s-a-nice-place-to-live-but-i-m-not-sure-i-want-to-stay-here/</guid>
      <description>From the Pew Research Center’s “2018 Local News Survey” is an interesting example of how the answer to a data analysis changes when you flip the question.
The data comes from the first two questions, which asked 34,897 people to rate the quality of living in their communities and how attached they feel to those communities.
LOCALRATING: Overall, how would you rate your community as a place to live?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump approval vs satisfaction with country&#39;s direction</title>
      <link>/2019/06/26/trump-approval-vs-satisfaction-with-country-s-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/26/trump-approval-vs-satisfaction-with-country-s-direction/</guid>
      <description>If you’re not sure whether you like the direction the country is heading toward, how likely are you to approve of President Trump’s job performance?
Taking a look at the Pew Research Center’s “September 2018 Political Survey,” the latest dataset publicly available on the center’s site, https://www.pewresearch.org/download-datasets/, the answer surprises me at least.
So if you’re not sure about the country’s direction, there’s a roughly equal chance that you approve of Trump’s job performance, disapprove or aren’t sure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random stuff on Bayes&#39; Theorem</title>
      <link>/2019/03/20/random-stuff-on-bayes-theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/20/random-stuff-on-bayes-theorem/</guid>
      <description>IntroJust some general notes as I try to learn how to use Bayes statistics. Take everything with a large grain of salt since there’s a reasonable chance I’ll get some of it wrong.
The underlying idea is that the Bayes’ Theorem allows you to refine your grasp on reality by using new evidence to modify your understanding.
Terminology:
P(A): probability of Event A.
P(B): probability of Event B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity of dog names in Allegheny County</title>
      <link>/2019/02/19/popularity-of-dog-names-in-allegheny-county/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/19/popularity-of-dog-names-in-allegheny-county/</guid>
      <description>Bella has usurped Molly but Buddy can’t be beat when it comes to the most frequent names on dog licenses in Allegheny County.
The data comes from the Western Pennsylvania Regional Data Center, https://data.wprdc.org/dataset/allegheny-county-dog-licenses. It includes dogs licensed within the county but not those licensed inside the city of Pittsburgh.
County dog owners like a lot of variety in their pets’ names. While top names for each gender accont for about 400 to 500 names, about 30,000 dogs are licensed every year with the number of unique names ranging from 7,031 in 2016 to 8,929 in 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>