<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jobs on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jobs on Brian&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pittsburgh jobs update</title>
      <link>/2019/11/07/pittsburgh-jobs-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/07/pittsburgh-jobs-update/</guid>
      <description>Pittsburgh fell behind on job creation in 2018Back in February I posted annual employment data from the Bureau of labor statistics that compared Pittsburgh to four groups of metro areaa. The groups were based on how much the metros gained or lost jobs compared to the 2006 totals.
In this update, you can see that Pittsburgh, which saw a mini boom while the rest of the country was struggling during the 2008 recession, has resumed its usual place of lagging behind the average metro area when it comes to employment growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pittsburgh&#39;s job trend</title>
      <link>/2019/02/21/pittsburgh-job-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/21/pittsburgh-job-trends/</guid>
      <description>How does Pittsburgh’s job trend compare to that of other metro areas?
Here’s the short answer showing the annual average total nonfarm payroll for each metro indexed to 2006.
The general trend line is shown in blue and Pittsburgh’s trend is shown in yellow. The metros are divided into four groups based on how their job growth generally compares to the overall trend line.
The clustering method I used put Pittsburgh in the “Slightly Better” group although that’s mainly based on its performance between 2008 and 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public sector jobs in Pittsburgh and other metros</title>
      <link>/2019/02/17/public-sector-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/17/public-sector-jobs/</guid>
      <description>How does Pittsburgh’s public sector employment compare to that of other metro areas? In this first glance, I’m going to focus on what percentage of the metro area’s jobs are government jobs.
The data comes from the Bureau of Labor Statistics monthly survey of state and local employment. I use the annual averages, so the latest data is for 2017.
Looking at 444 metro areas in the 50 states, the District of Columbia and Puerto Rico, the concentration of public-sector employment in 2017 ranged from a low of 6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
